Paula Rodríguez Cloud engineer

- ★ linkedin.com/pauloba
- ★ github.com/pauloba
- ★ stackoverflow.com/pauloba

In 2016 I finished a degree in Computer science from Vigo University.

I have hands-on experience architecting on public clouds since 2017, with a background of sysadmin, cybersec and tech support.

I have a collaborative mindset, I believe in teamplay as a life strategy.

Tech stack

Anthos Svc. Mesh

Kubernetes

Prometheus

SonarQube

Terragrunt

Terraform

Grafana

Datadog

Anchore

Jenkins

Docker

Helm

ifrog

GCP

AWS

SQL

git

Scripting

Python

Bash

Methodologies

IaC + CI/CD

Kaizen

Agile - Scrum

Git flow

Peer review

Merge Requests

DevSecOps

FinOps

Experience

Vodafone [Oct 2023 - now] Platform engineer

Configuration and administration of **AWS** cloud infra resources using **DevOps** practices. Collaboration with **architectural** decisions for business solutions and platforms.

Designing blueprints for multi-tenant platform capabilities, defining tenant roll-out strategies, writing **infra as code** and designing and configuring **pipelines** for apps and infra releases.

FonYou [Jul 2021 - Sep 2023] Cloud Sysadmin

Deployment, **operation** and **support** for cloud-based production systems, ensuring the availability, performance, scalability and security of the systems.

Automation of processes and operations + **support** and **maintenance** of company-developed applications.

Google through Webhelp [Jan 2019 - June 2021]

Subject Matter Expert

Help customers *troubleshoot* and *fix GCP integrations*.

Bug reporting, and bug quality review.

Mentor and *guide* colleagues to *improve* the SLAs,SLOs and SLIs.

Create, improve and maintain internal documentation.

Internal *training* for the infrastructure team.

Soft skills

Empathy
Teamwork
Work ethic
Critical thinking
Active listening
Documentation
Resourcefulness

Languages

Spanish - native English - proficient

Education

Computer science degree
at <u>UVigo</u> [2012 - 2016]
Final project
pauloba/latch-plugin-mediawiki

High level trade school, Computer Programming at CPR Daniel Castelao [2003 - 2005]

Professional training course: Java Programmer and analyst 11 months [**2011**]

Experience

Google through Sellbytel [Aug 2017 - Jan 2019]

Technical Solutions Representative

Triage, diagnosis and **solve issues** related to **GCP services**, through email, phone and videoconference.

Experience with a Salesforce-based ticketing system.

Technologies: GCE, GKE, VPC networks, Container Registry, Deployment manager, Pub/Sub, GCP APIs, IAM & Security.

Enxendra Technologies [Nov 2016 – Apr 2017]

Level 2 support and QA unit testing

Patch deployment, **UNIX sysadmin** (syslog, tomcat, crontab, ssh).

Java unit testing with Groovy and Spock.

Experience with the Atlassian stack: Jira, confluence, bitbucket.

Technologies: docker, IntelliJ, eclipse, SoapUI, postman, MySQL, Java, Ant, Maven, SpringBoot, Groovy and Spock.

Telefónica Security Op. Center

Nov 2015 - Oct 2016 Level 2 security technician

Coordination with **CSIRT** / **CERT**, **ISPs**, web hostings, registrars and registrants to stop and **prevent global fraud attempts**.

Incident reporting: *analysis* and *reports* for final customers.

Real time **network monitoring** and **security incident analysis** with Cisco FirePOWER/SourceFire/FireSight sources for QRadar.

ORadar (IBM SIEM) rule adjustment to fine-tune detections.

Online fraud prevention: referer analysis, bank transfer analysis, monitoring of suspicious phishing connections.

Real time analysis and mitigation for Bank Trojans, halcash.

Experience with the SIRIOS ticketing system and ITSM Remedy.

Experience

Conferences

Organizing committee

r2con [since 2017]

Merchandising
Schedule planning
Website
Community manager
Organizing speakers/trainers
Audio testing w/music artists

National Association for Information Security

[Jan – Sept 2015] General Secretary

The **project** was motivated by approval of **BOE-A-2015-344**

Website sysadmin via Wordpress panel and ssh.

Merchandising design w/Gimp+Inkscape: t-shirts, banners, logo.

Vigo University [2010 - 2013] Sysadmin

Installation, **configuration** and **maintenance** of the Campus software and hardware.

Management of LDAP systems, SquirrelMail, print servers, network monitoring software.

Restoration and **recovery** of **hardware** from old computers.

Network **backup management** with Clonezilla + Norton Ghost.

Tech support for students and teachers of the Campus labs.

Self-employment [2007 - 2015] Teacher

English and **mathematics teacher** for high school students.